var quiz = {
    "JS": [
    {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is the highest common factor of the numbers 30 and 132?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "6",
    "b": "25",
    "c": "8",
    "d": "16"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "6",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "123+4-5+67-89 = ? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "104",
    "b": "100",
    "c": "80"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "100",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "From the number 0 to the number 1000, the letter “A” appears only in?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "100",
    "b": "900",
    "c": "1000"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "1000",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 4,
    "question": " What is next in the following number series: 256, 289, 324, 361 . . . ?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "367",
    "b": "400",
    "c": "500"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "400",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "At a Christmas party, everyone shook hands with everyone else. There were a total of 66 handshakes that happened during the party. How many people were present? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "15",
    "b": "12",
    "c": "11",
    "d": "9",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "12",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "What is the name of a triangle that has two sides of the same length?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "isosceles",
    "b": "scalene",
    "c": "obtuse",
    "d": "acute",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "isosceles",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "All natural numbers are whole numbers. However, not all whole numbers can be considered natural ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "True",
    "b": "False",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "True",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "You are given a 3-digit number. The second digit of this number is four times bigger than the third digit. The first digit of the number is 3 less than the second digit. What is the number? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "151",
    "b": "160",
    "c": "141",
    "d": " 200",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "141",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 9,
    "question": " How many hours are there in a year (rounded to the nearest hour)?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "8720",
    "b": "8760",
    "c": "9000",
    "d": "None of the above."
    }
    ],
    "answer": "8760",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "A man is currently 4 times older than his son. In 10 years, the man will be three times older than his son. What is the man’s age presently?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "90",
    "b": "80",
    "c": "70",
    "d": "50",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "80",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which number is best represented in binary as 100? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "3",
    "b": "4",
    "c": "6"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "4",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "What 3 numbers result in the same answer when they are added or multiplied altogether? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "1,2 and 4.",
    "b": "2,4 and 8.",
    "c": "3,4 and 6.",
    "d": "1,2 and 3."
    }
    ],
    "answer": "1,2 and 3.",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Sarah read a novel in 20 days. She made it a habit to read 16 pages every day for the first 15 days. She then started reading 18 pages every day for the last 5 days. How many pages was the book? .",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "320 pages.",
    "b": "300 pages.",
    "c": "330 pages."
    }
    ],
    "answer": "330 pages.",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "27 is a perfect cube. If true then what is the perfect cube of 27? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "9",
    "b": "6",
    "c": "3"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "3",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 15,
    "question": " An equilateral triangle has two of its sides equal. ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "True",
    "b": "False",
   
    }
    ],
    "answer": "False",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Icosahedrons have how many equal sides? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "30",
    "b": "20",
    "c": "25",
    "d": "60"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "20",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "The use of Arabic Numerals is invented in what country?    ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "India",
    "b": "Saudi Arabia",
    "c": "Dubai",
    "d": "Iran"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "India",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "What does the term ‘crore’ mean? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Four million",
    "b": "Three million",
    "c": "Ten million"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Ten million",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Apart from one, I am the first positive number that is both a square and a cube. ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "24",
    "b": "54",
    "c": "64",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "64",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "What does the term “Giga” refer to? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "One Billion",
    "b": "One million",
    "c": "One trillion"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "One Billion",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Calculate the quotient of 150 and 3. ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "450",
    "b": "50",
    "c": "100",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "50",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "What is the only prime number that is even? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "2",
    "b": "4",
    "c": "6",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "2",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Which number is equivalent to 3^(4)÷3^(2)?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "6",
    "b": "9",
    "c": "8",
    "d": "5"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "9",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "I am an odd number. Take away one letter and I become even. What number am I?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "seven",
    "b": "five",
    "c": "six"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "seven",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "How many feet are in a mile? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "5280",
    "b": "5000",
    "c": "5600",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "5280",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    }
    ]
    }
    var quizApp = function () {
    this.score = 0;
    this.qno = 1;
    this.currentque = 0;
    var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
    this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = cque;
    if (this.currentque < totalque) {
    $("#tque").html(totalque);
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
    $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
    $("#question-options").html("");
    for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
    $("#question-options").append(
    "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
    "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
    "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
    "</span></label>"
    );
    }
    }
    }
    if (this.currentque <= 0) {
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
    }
    if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
    $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
    for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
    this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
    }
    return this.showResult(this.score);
    }
    }
    this.showResult = function (scr) {
    $("#result").addClass('result');
    $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
    for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
    var res;
    if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
    res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
    } else {
    res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
    }
    $("#result").append(
    '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
    '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
    '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
    '</div>'
    );
    }
    }
    this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
    var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
    option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
    option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
    option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
    if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
    }
    } else {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
    }
    }
    this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
    this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
    }
    }
    var jsq = new quizApp();
    var selectedopt;
    $(document).ready(function () {
    jsq.displayQuiz(0);
    $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
    //var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
    $(this).prop("checked", true);
    selectedopt = $(this).val();
    });
    });
    $('#next').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(1);
    });
    $('#previous').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
    });
